clearfit.com 2014-11-21

# Privacy Policy & Anti-Spam Policy - ClearFit

**MAINTAINING THE PRIVACY AND SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION IS EXTREMELY IMPORTANT TO CLEARFIT.**

This Privacy Policy applies to ClearFit. This Privacy Policy describes how ClearFit collects and uses the personal information you provide to our Site: http://www.clearfit.com and other related ClearFit sites.  It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this policy you should first contact ClearFit Customer Service at [info@ClearFit.com](mailto:info@ClearFit.com).

**We want to ensure that your experience with ClearFit is a comfortable, safe and secure one.   **It is important to us that you are aware of exactly where and how both general information concerning your visit to our Site and your submitted personal information is or may be used. This will be described in this Privacy Policy below.

### Privacy Information for Users of the Site – Collection, Use and Disclosure

When you arrive at ClearFit.com you may visit various areas of our Site and click on certain links and buttons to search for and review additional information about career opportunities, potential candidates, and the ClearFit Program.

### Log Files

ClearFit gathers information by logging IP addresses, browser type, operating system, referring/exit page, date/time stamp, and aggregate survey results. The logged information is only used in the aggregate and is not tied to personal information unless you have registered to join the Site. For example, we will keep a record of the aggregate number of visitors who access each area of our Site, which areas of our Site receive the heaviest traffic and what services offered through ClearFit are utilized most frequently. The information collected by us will assist in the continual process of updating and improving our Site so that your visit to ClearFit will be as rewarding and complete as possible. From time to time we may share this aggregate statistical information with our participating Employers and partners.

### Using the Services

Candidates who join the Site (as defined in the Terms of Use) to obtain Services receive Career Feedback Reports.  Employers will receive special products, pricing and promotions that are not otherwise available. Candidates can learn more about their work-related personality and motivation characteristics and learn what jobs and Employers fit them best.  In order to provide our unique service to Users, we are required to collect relevant personal information, including psychometric, job search, and recruitment-related information during User registration.

For Candidates, this personal information includes the results of their ClearFit Online Survey, employment history, past education, skills, certifications and contact information and such personal information is stored in a secure third-party cloud environment. We call this the Candidate’s personal profile information.

For Employers, collected information includes their job description criteria, candidates, hiring criteria, including education, personality, motivation, experience criteria and contact information and this information is stored in a secure third-party cloud. We call this the employer’s job profile and Registration information.

Employers collect personal information when they obtain the results of the psychometric survey answered by Candidates, which involves a series of questions and employment/education-related criteria which compares Candidates against Employers’ corresponding job-related criteria in the database, based on personality, interests and other job-related criteria. The Career Feedback Reports Candidates receive as part of the ClearFit application process are theirs alone and completely confidential. Candidates always control who has access to their personal information. Participating Employers may access Candidates’ personal profile data and the interpretation of raw survey scores to create their own reports, but not their personal information without that Candidate’s consent. When a Candidate applies to an Employer using the Site, they consenting to the use of their personal information by that Employer solely in connection with the hiring process to make more accurate hiring decisions, based on how candidates’ personal profiles match against their job profiles.

All Users acknowledge and agree that their personal information collected by ClearFit may stored, transferred, and processed across national boundaries in any of the countries where ClearFit and its affiliates and subsidiaries maintain offices, including, without limitation, the United States, United Kingdom, France, Belgium, Germany, Japan, Brazil, Russia, Mexico, Philippines, Australia and of course, Canada.  These jurisdictions may have data protection laws differ from those of Canada and as a result, personal information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in those jurisdictions according to laws in those jurisdictions.  For example, information may be shared in response to valid demands or requests from government authorities, courts and law enforcement officials in those countries or when required by law where we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with an appropriate law enforcement investigation, current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Site. Subject to applicable laws in such other jurisdictions, ClearFit will use reasonable efforts to ensure that appropriate protections are in place to maintain protections on personal information that are equivalent to those that apply in Canada.

### Feedback/Communication and Choice

From time-to-time our Site may contact Users via surveys, email communications, or contests. Participation in these surveys, email communications, or contests is completely voluntary and the User therefore has a choice whether or not to disclose their job search-related information. Information requested may include any job search-related information, such as contact information (such as name and address), and demographic information (such as zip code). Information collected will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use, satisfaction and services of this Site.

When you register on our Site (whether as a Candidate or Employer), we will receive specific information about you, such as your name, address, email address, telephone number, etc. In return for the services that you receive from ClearFit, from time to time we may contact you in an effort to determine the level of satisfaction with the services provided through ClearFit.com, or to advise you of services that may be of interest to you.

As a Candidate we may contact you about opportunities that fit your job profile or personal profile via email.  You may also elect to receive mobile notifications and/or text to the mobile phone number you provide. If you opt-in to the text alerts, expect to receive up to 5 messages per month.  Unsubscribe from this service by emailing [info@clearfit.com](mailto:info@clearfit.com). There is no charge for this service, but messages and data rates may apply. If you have questions please contact our Customer Service team at [info@clearfit.com](mailto:info@clearfit.com).

As an employer, we may contact you via email with news about our company and product, hiring and business resources, assistance with using the ClearFit application, and special promotions.  If you are actively using ClearFit for hiring, you will receive communication from ClearFit staff about the status of your job and notifications when new candidates apply. Unsubscribe from these messages by emailing [info@clearfit.com](mailto:info@clearfit.com). You may also elect to receive mobile notification,  there is no charge for this service, but messages and data rates may apply. If you have questions please contact our Customer Service team at [info@clearfit.com](mailto:info@clearfit.com).

You agree that ClearFit may, as part of its services to you, communicate with you, or initiate communication with you on behalf of a 3rd party, through your ClearFit account or through other means made available through your contact information such as email, phone, or postal mail as permitted by applicable law.

Employers are given the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our Site at the point when we email them to confirm their registration, and provide a link to enable opt-out. Any Users who no longer wish to receive contact from ClearFit or from our partners may opt-out of receiving further communications from a particular party by replying with unsubscribe in the subject line in the email or email us at [info@clearfit.com](mailto:info@clearfit.com).

### How else is personal information used?

ClearFit may, on occasion, share some or all of your personal information with third party service providers for processing and data analysis.. For Employers, in order to process credit card transactions, ClearFit must share your credit card information with our credit card processors to complete our billing process. For all users, in order to analyze our sites’ performance, we use emails to identify users inside our third party systems. These third parties may be located in other jurisdictions that may have data protection laws differ from those of Canada and as a result, personal information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in those jurisdictions according to laws in those jurisdictions. Therefore, your information may be processed and stored in other jurisdictions and, as a result, other governments, courts, or law enforcement or regulatory agencies may be able to obtain disclosure of your information through foreign laws. As discussed earlier, subject to applicable laws in such other jurisdictions, ClearFit will use reasonable efforts to ensure that appropriate protections are in place to maintain protections on personal information that are equivalent to those that apply in Canada. Regardless, all third party service providers that do work for ClearFit are bound by various legal agreements that do not permit them to use the Users’ personal information except as to otherwise specifically provided and explicitly prohibit them from using such personal information for their own purposes (including their own marketing purposes or otherwise disclose such information to any third parties). We may disclose and ultimately transfer personal information in the context of a business transaction involving the reorganization, acquisition or amalgamation of our business or the sale of all or some of our assets provided that the personal information disclosed is required to be used for the purposes permitted by this Privacy Policy by the entity acquiring this information. In such event, after a reorganization, acquisition, amalgamation or sale has occurred, we will use reasonable efforts to notify you (either by posting notice on the Site or by email to you at the last known email address) that such a business transaction has occurred.

### Blog/Testimonials

If you use a blog or testimonial on this Site, you should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. For testimonials, we do obtain the customer’s consent prior to posting their name along with their testimonial. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums. If you want to remove your personal information that is being displayed on our Site under public pages, please contact us at [info@ClearFit.com](mailto:info@clearfit.com).

### Use of Cookies

We use “cookies” to track User activities on our Sites. These cookies permit us to remember a User who has visited different areas of our Site, so that the User will not have to re-enter his or her password on multiple occasions. We use third-party tracking services that employ cookies to track non-personal information about visitors to our Site. Our services can determine whether you are a new or returning visitor, the time of the current visit, and what the referrer site the User came from. We also use this to track page and site usage on our Site.

### 3rd Party Tracking

The use of cookies and tags by our partners and service providers is not covered by our Privacy Policy. We do not have access or control over these cookies or tags. Our third party partners employ clear gifs, images, and scripts that help them better manage content on our Site.

### Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting

We partner with third party ad networks and other parties to either display advertising on our Site or to manage our advertising on other sites.  Our ad network partners use cookies, tags and Web beacons to collect non-personal information about your activities on this and other web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests.

### Social Media Widgets

Our Site also includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Please note that the collection of your personal information by these Features (including the collection of your IP address) are governed by the Privacy Policy of the company providing it.

### Notice of Changes to this Privacy Policy

If we decide to revise or change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes prominently on ClearFit.com so that you will always know what personal information we gather, how we might use that information, and to whom we may disclose it. Please check the Site frequently for information concerning revisions or changes to our Privacy Policy.

If at any point we decide to use personal information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify Users by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective.

### Site and Service Updates

We may also send Users our Site and service announcement updates. Users are not able to unsubscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the service. We communicate with the User to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to your account via email.

### Opting Out/Deactivation/Access

You can elect to be excluded from any surveys, contests or announcements that will be sent out by ClearFit at any time.  Employers may do this by going to the “Account” tab. In these areas we may use your information to make you aware of additional products and services which may be of interest to you, or to contact you regarding Site changes. You may access and edit all of your personal information at any time. We will retain your personal information for as long as you remain a User of the ClearFit Services or for as long as legally required. Users may terminate, correct, update, amend, delete/remove their account with ClearFit by sending a request to our customer service department through the ‘Contact Us’ section of our Site or by emailing us at [info@ClearFit.com](mailto:info@clearfit.com).

### Links

This Site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that ClearFit is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our Users to be aware when they leave our Site and to read the Privacy Policy of each and every web site that collects personal information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by this Site.

When you use “Share This” to bookmark and share our products and Site, you will be taken to a third party site. Please note that these third party sites’ privacy policies govern the collection and use of the information collected on those sites.

### Security

ClearFit recognizes the importance of providing a secure environment for personal information both online and offline.  ClearFit websites are hosted entirely on a cloud platform which supports secure access protocols, firewalls, and private networks.

ClearFit processes credit card transactions through a PCI certified partner.

Additionally, all of our Users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices.   All employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Annually, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers’ information is protected.

Despite our considerable efforts, we are not and will not be responsible in the event that a third party (for example, a hacker) evades our security measures and gains access to the central database, and, subsequently, your personal information.

You are solely responsible for safeguarding and maintaining the secrecy of your account, passwords and/or any account information in your possession or control.

If you have any questions about the security at our Site, you can send an email to [info@ClearFit.com](mailto:info@clearfit.com).

### Tell Us What You Think

If, at any time, you have questions or concerns about your privacy, please feel free to contact us at [info@ClearFit.com](mailto:info@clearfit.com) by mail at 150 Eglinton Avenue East, Suite 803, Toronto, Ontario, Canada, M4P 1E8 or by telephone at 1-416-482-2252.

Last Updated: October 7, 2014.

## Anti-Spam Policy

### Spam Defined

ClearFit.com strictly prohibits members engaging in spam and other tactics which may constitute abuse of the Internet in order to seek referrals. What is Spam? Generally speaking, activities which would constitute spam include the sending of: (i) unsolicited commercial e-mail, (ii) unsolicited bulk e-mail, (iii) mass e-mail, and/or (iv) junk e-mail, containing a message that advertises goods or services. The defining feature of spam is that the e-mail is sent to someone without their prior consent or in the absence of a previous relationship between the sender and the recipient. Spam is the electronic equivalent of the junk mail you receive in your postal mailbox every day or those telemarketers who call at dinner time!

Spam can take several different forms. When someone logs on to Usenet or message boards and sends or posts messages which are unrelated to the topic of discussion, that’s spam. In addition, the sending of an electronic mail message addressed to a recipient with whom the sender does not have an existing business or personal relationship or is not sent at the request of, or with the express consent of, the recipient constitutes spam. The act of engaging in activities which constitute spam is called spamming.

Other types of Internet abuse may also qualify as spam. Examples include, spamming of chat rooms and spamming via Internet Relay Chat or “Instant Messaging” systems (such as ICQ). In reality, the various methods of spamming will continue to evolve with the Internet as new ways of online communication between people develop.

### We Don’t Like Spam

No one likes sorting through junk mail or talking to telemarketers, but spam is even worse! Electronic junk mail costs recipients of spam more time and money than it costs the sender. The unwitting recipient of spam is required to download, sort through, and identify what e-mail is legitimate and what e-mail is junk e-mail, and then discard it. If the recipient pays for Internet access by the hour or minute, then sorting through spam messages leads to increased time online, which translates into higher monthly bills from their Internet Service Provider.

Conduct on the Internet is governed by an unwritten set of rules called ‘Netiquette,’ and one of those rules is that it’s not acceptable to send out unsolicited mass e-mail. Spam can also slow the performance of the Internet. There have been instances where large volumes of spam have slowed down e-mail delivery for hours (or even days!). Spam sometimes causes computers on the Internet to crash. Most importantly, we feel that spamming is just plain rude.

### Our Anti-Spam Policy

ClearFit’s referral program is meant to encourage people to introduce the benefits of ClearFit to their friends and family, and to people with whom they transact with online. We do not intend to, nor do we encourage, the use of spam under any circumstances.

Upon receipt of a credible complaint concerning spamming, ClearFit may immediately suspend the membership of the individual who is alleged to have conducted the spamming. A suspension of membership privileges is intended to prevent a possible spammer from continuing to benefit from their activities by prohibiting the registration of referrals or the accruing of additional referral payments. If the spamming incident is not verified after a through investigation by ClearFit , the suspension may be lifted and all referrals and referral payments which have accrued during the period of suspension will be restored. ClearFit may, but is not obligated to, lift a suspension imposed on a member due to alleged spamming activities.

Anyone who is found by ClearFit to have spammed other Internet users in an attempt to gain referral bonuses will lose their ClearFit membership privileges and their account will be terminated. Any referral bonuses acquired in the spammer’s account will be confiscated by ClearFit . Any monies which remain in the spammer’s account after confiscation of referral bonuses will be returned to the account holder.

### How to Report Spammers

If you feel that a member of ClearFit has spammed you, please contact info@ClearFit.com. Be sure to include evidence of the spamming such as a copy of the e-mail, posting or message with full message headers or the usenet message. It would assist our efforts in confirming your complaint if you include any other information that can be used to identify the parties involved. An incomplete complaint may result in delays in the enforcement of our Anti-Spam Policy.

### How do I avoid engaging in Spam when making Referrals?

We created the ClearFit Referral Program to reward our members for introducing the ClearFit Program to their friends and family, and to people they transact with online. There are many ways in which you can participate in our referral program without resorting to spam. Here are a few guidelines to help you:

* Make sure you know the Person.

You can tell anyone who you know and whom you think might benefit from our service about ClearFit.com and the ClearFit Program. This includes friends, family, business and other acquaintances. In addition you should feel free to talk to anyone who asks you for information about ClearFit.com or the ClearFit Program.

### * Spreading the Word!

Email is the fastest and easiest way to tell your friends, family, business and other acquaintances about ClearFit.com and the ClearFit Program, however, you can also use old-fashioned word-of mouth to tell your friends about us. When you visit the ClearFit Referral Center, you will be able to select a referral e-mail that you can personalize or forward as is to interested parties. In the e-mail, we include your User Name, identifying you as the referring party. When your friend enters your User Name when they sign up, you are automatically eligible for a referral bonus whenever they are hired successfully by a ClearFit company.

Please use the ClearFit Referral Program responsibly. We strictly enforce our Anti Spam Policy!
